Kevin Snijders

Date of birth: 6 april 1993 Birthplace: Purmerend Nationality: The Netherlands



Web Developer with over 2 years of Front-end experience and a passion for building beautiful things. Capable of working on Back-end as I graduated as Software Engineering. Well in communicating and not afraid to share my opinion. Like learning new technologies and open for using any language.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Web Developer | Personal website | Purmerend | 2019 - present day

Key Qualifications & Responsibilities

- Implemented a Progressive Single-page
 Application from concept through deployment.
- Created a custom theme from scratch without using a boilerplate.
- Implemented localStorage whenever offline mode is active
- Implemented tests with Jest, Enzyme and react-test-renderer.
- Developed and implemented a Node Express server with a Postgres database.

Internship Full Stack Developer | Sofa Superstars | Amsterdam | February 2017 - July 2018

Key Qualifications & Responsibilities

- Wrote a thesis about a cross-site messaging system with near-real-time delivery.
- Gathered and documented requirements with Use-Cases.
- Implemented an application from concept through deployment.
- Implemented a React component library with Rollup from concept through deployment.
- Set up a WebSocket API integration.
- Gave a product demo every two weeks.

Front-end Developer | Sofa Superstars | Amsterdam | September 2015 - February 2017

Key Qualifications & Responsibilities

- Implemented websites, and landing pages from concept through deployment.
- Implemented old browser compatibility code.
- Replaced pieces of VanillaJS code for React components.
- Responsible for fixing hotfix issues as pixel perfect, responsiveness, and bugs.
- Assessed UX and UI designs for technical feasibility.
- Collaborated with team members to implement new feature developments.
- Participated in Scrum meetings with the team.
- Mentored the Front-end intern.

Internship Multimedia | Youngbits | Purmerend | September 2013 - January 2014

Key Qualifications & Responsibilities

- Implemented WordPress websites from concept through deployment.
- Learned to create prototypes with Photoshop.
- Assessed client ideas and whishes for technical feasibility.

EDUCATION

Software Engineering | Hogeschool van Amsterdam | Amsterdam | September 2014 - September 2018

Relevant Coursework: Startup Analytics, Strategic Management, Prototyping, Automated Software validation, Parallel Computing, Research Design, Architecture & Design, Information Visualization, Object-Oriented Programming, Datastructures,

Applicatieontwikkelaar | Horizon college | Purmerend | September 2010 - September 2014

SKILLS

- Creating web applications.
- Maintaining, optimizing, troubleshooting, and improving websites.
- Implementation of website and landing pages from concept through deployment.

Knowledge: HTML5, JavaScript, CSS, Sass, Bootstrap, jQuery, Wordpress, React, Git, Redux, Jest, Gulp, Webpack, Babel, Node.js, Progressive web apps, npm, ESLint, Prettier, JSON, Java, Python, Django, Databases (PostgreSQL and MySQL), CircleCI, Github Pages, Heroku, JIRA, and Trello.

Project management: JIRA, Trello, and Agile (Scrum)

SOFT SKILLS

Communication, Flexibility, Patience, Perseverance, Teamwork, Solution-oriented, Stress resistant, Willingness to learn.

LANGUAGES

Dutch and English

REFERENCE

Upon request